Jack Staffen

New York, NY, 10014 | 917-881-6989 | jackstaffen.studio@gmail.com GitHub: jastaffen | Linkedin | Personal Website

Full Stack Software Engineer

Experience building Full Stack web applications using JavaScript and JavaScript frameworks like React, Redux, and React Native in the frontend, and Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and SQL in the backend.

Pursuing music and audio engineering/production gave me considerable experience striking the balance between the immense technical knowledge and boundless creativity required as a musician in control of their product from start to finish.

I am excited to employ this unique balance that is also intrinsic to software engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript: JavaScript (ES6+), React, React Native, React Navigation, Redux

Ruby: Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Web & Data: HTML, CSS, SQL, PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Gust -Github: Frontend, Backend | Demo

An app where users can vote on songs they want a particular artist to perform live, can follow artists, and can discover upcoming shows by the artists they follow.

- Built the frontend using **React Native** and an intuitive user interface with **React Navigation**.
- Built the backend using Ruby on Rails as a RESTful API with PostgreSQL to persist the data.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Managed client-side state data using Redux.
- Retrieved data from the **Spotify API** and **SongKick API** so users could search for artists, albums, and tracks, and find upcoming concerts by artists they follow, respectively.
- Recorded user's geolocation, and translated coordinates into an address using the Google Maps API.

Motel Home Music Site - Github | Demo

A simple portfolio site showcasing my music scoring, design, and audio editing work.

- Constructed the site with React and React Router.
- Utilized **flexbox**, **media queries**, and **CSS** animations to build an interactive and responsive user interface.
- Followed wireframes made by a graphic designer that employ a minimalist/internet brutalist aesthetic.

EXPERIENCE

Songwriter, Producer, and Front Person in Purr and Jack and Eliza

11/2015 - Present

- Composes, records, and performs original music nationally and internationally.
- Composed and co-produced 2 LPs and one EP with critical acclaim through independent record labels.
- Manages social media accounts, organizes and leads rehearsals, and general day-to-day band goings on.

Co-founder of Motel Home Music

11/2015 - Present

- Produces and records commercial musical scores and edits sound for digital ads and independent films.
- Utilizes expertise in recording softwares, Pro Tools and Logic Pro, to create professional edits and recordings.
- Communicates and coordinates with clients to cater to their wants and needs and construct the desired product.
- Manages finances and taxes for the LLC.

Private Music Teacher

09/2016 - 09/2018

 Taught guitar, vocals, drums, piano, songwriting, and recording technologies to children and young adults between the ages of 7-18.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

10/2019 - 01/2020

An immersive, highly intensive web development program that accepts around 6% of applicants and has a 93% placement rate Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering Track

New York University

Graduated 05/2017

Bachelor of Arts from Gallatin School of Individualized Study (with a concentration in Art History, Political Science, and the Social Sciences)

Cumulative GPA - 3.78